

# RUNGROJ PREECHAPAKDEE

Executive Creative Director / Digital Marketing Director

Tel. +6682-090-7888

Email. rungroj.p@gmail.com

Line ID. nueng-suptar BKK, Thailand

## Expertise -

360 Degrees Creative Solution

On Air / Online / On Mobile / On Ground Strategic Ideation & Execution

Experience / Engagement / Involvement

Visual&Typographic Craft

Stunning Copywriting & Art Direction

Digital Thinking & Marketing

Innovative / Interactive / Effective

King of Content

User Centric Storytelling

Queen of UX/UI

User Friendly / Simple Journey

Teamwork Motivation

Team Leader / Mentor / Player / Inspirer

## Computer

- Mac/PC
- Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver)
- MS Office (Powerpoint, Word, Outlook)
- Keynote, Pages, iMovie, iPhoto
- Facetime, Skype, Line, Whatsapp

## Language

## Summary

A copywriting-based EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF CREATIVE AND DIGITAL MARKETING who has had 15 years of work experience at Top Leading Advertising Agencies (Ogilvy, McCann, SC Matchbox) and Corporate Sides (Central Group, Shin Corp., Sanook.com, GMM Grammy), focused on holistic idea & strategic -driven Integrated Marketing Communications. I won local and global creative awards (Cannes Lions, Adfest, Adman, B.A.D, TACT) as well as new business pitchings based on the powerful pace of challenging management and teamwork player&mentor.

## **Creative Award Winnings**

- 1 Best APAC Airline Website 2014: www.thaiairways.com
- 2 Gold Cannes Lions 2013 in Media: Coca-Cola (Open Happiness IMC Campaign)
- 1 Bronze ADFEST 2011 in Cyber: TAT (Speaking Translator Mobile App)
- 1 Bronze ADMAN 2011 in Mobile Advertising: TAT (Speaking Translator Mobile App)
- 1 Best B.A.D 2010 in Banner: TAT (Speaking Translator Mobile App)
- 1 Cert. B.A.D 2010 in Innovative: TAT (Speaking Translator Mobile App)
- 1 Gold TACT 2006 in Internet Advertising: AIS Halloween Campaign
- 1 Cert. B.A.D 2005 in Website Design: AIS Halloween Campaign
- 1 Best B.A.D 2004 in Website Design: AIS Branding Campaign

### **Experience**

Sep 2015 -

Digital Marketing Director

Present

GMM Grammy PCL.

Head of Digital Business & Creative Marketing and key member of Senior Management for Total Music Solutions including Artists, Branded Content Creation, Digital Campaigns, Merchandise,

eCommerce, Digital TV.

Mar 2015 -Jul 2015 **Executive Creative Director** 

Edge Asia (Thailand)

Country Head of Creative and Senior Management for Integrated and Digital Marketing Communications. Also, create and lead team to generate the greatest masterpieces (from conception to completion) and pitchings based on holistic ideas and multi-platform solutions.

Apr 2013 -Feb 2015 Senior Creative Director

Sanook Online Ltd. (Tencent Holdings Group)

Head of Creative Team for Integrated & Digital Marketing

Communications who creates holistic ideas and plans creative strategy & user journey as well as directs the creative function so that the environment, team, capabilities, tools, processes, expectations, work style and other elements support the strategic goals and target insight.

Oct 2011 -Mar 2013 Senior Integrated Creative

Ogilvy & Mather Advertising (Thailand)

Creative & Copywriter Producer for Digital Marketing Communications who creates big ideas, concept boards, storyboards and content plots for Interactive Communications, Experiences and Engagements, providing impactful concepts, thematic visual & copy, creative directions, and leadership for client presentations & new business pitches.

Mar 2011 -Sep 2011 Creative Group Head

Mcfiva

Head of Creative Team and key member of Senior Management for

## **Certificated Training**

• "Digital Creative" trained by McCann Worldgroup.

"Object-Oriented Application using with JAVA" trained by King Mongkut Institute of Technology Ladkrabang.

- "2D Animator" trained by Sipa/ IMAGIMAX Co., Ltd.
- "Creative Advertising" trained by Amarin Printing Plc.
- "Professional Web Designer" trained by NetDesign School.
- "Customer Service" trained by Thai Airways International Plc.
- "The Power of Co-Branding" trained by Samsung Thailand.
- "Cannes Winners 2014 & Multi-Screen Marketing Communications" trained by Marketeer.
- "Spark Conference for Digital Trend & Marketing 2014" trained by Thumbsup.
- "CRM through CEM" trained by SC Matchbox.

#### **Interest & Passion**

- Real Estate & Retail
   (Architectural/Interior/Landscape Design)
- Creative Design & Advertising (Digitally, Visually/Typographically)
- Innovative Gadgets
   (Smartphones, Tablet, Google Glasses)
- Entertainment (Movies, Series, Musics, Games)
- Fashion (Models, Dress, Accessories)
- Health & Sport (Spa, Fitness, Backpacking)
- Food & Beverage (Wine, Coffee, Bakery, Spaghetti)

#### Career Goal -

Chief Creative Officer, Chairman

Integrated and Digital Marketing Communications. Work closely with all team (Client Service, Strategists, Graphic Designers, Project Managers, Programmers) to create the best creative solutions and new business pitches.

Mar 2007 - Senior Creative Copywriter
Feb 2011 McCann Worldgroup (Thailand)

Create Copywriting and Supervise Digital, IMC, CRM, Direct Marketing: Mobile/Facebook App, Online Activities, Websites, Online Banner, eDM, Gamification, Flash Presentation, Multimedia, etc. Create big ideas and key messages for Digital Campaigns, IMC, CRM, PR, Direct Marketing, Radio Spot. Work closely with art directors and strategists to plan impactful communications for each digital touchpoint. Recruit, supervise and manage outsource suppliers.

Sep 2002 - Creative Copywriter
Feb 2007 SC Matchbox (Shin Corp)

Create copywriting and idea for digital & interactive projects (Website, Online Banner, Flash Presentation, Multimedia, etc.). Act as Online Creative and Webmaster of AIS and Serenade. Create big ideas and contents for the interactive campaigns at AIS Shop, offering monthly privileges and activities via microsite and touch screen.

May 2000 - Senior Web Editor Aug 2002 Pop Network (Central Group)

Act as Web Creative Editor, Online Writer/Rewriter, Proof-reader, Co-producer, and Project Manager for multimedia and websites production. Be Online Columnist and Online News Reporter for the entertainment channel (Movie & Music) of the clients and company's portal website. Create, produce and maintain all content of the clients and company's website.

#### **Education**

2005 - 2007 Master of IT Management
 King Mongkut Institute of Technology Ladkrabang
 2002 - 2005 Bachelor of Communications Art (Advertising)
 Sukhothai Thammatiraj Open University
 1996 - 1999 Bachelor of Arts (Italian)
 Chulalongkorn University

#### **Portfolio**

My Top 16 Showcases. For all ones, let me present you in the interview session.







IMC: One Email One Tree



Mobile App: Speak Thai





Interactive Movie: Born to C... IMC: Signature of Response IMC: Borrow Cruze in 3 Hrs





IMC: Game in the Air



Viral: Flying Bags



Webisode: Postcard from N...



Mobile App: Hair Health Ch...



IMC: I Hate Border



Viral: Unexpectable Day





Mobile App: Thai Shine T-S... IMC: Good Morning Thailand Interactive Book: Thai Pride

